<part id="aravis-overview">
	<title>Overview</title>

	<chapter id="aravis-introduction">
		<title>Introduction</title>

		<para>
			Aravis is a GObject based library for the control and the video stream
			acquisition of digital cameras.
		</para>

		<para>
			While using GenICam xml files for the description of the camera
			registers, it does not try to be a complete implementation of the
			Genicam API as described in the GenAPI GenICam document. Nevertheless,
			a good knowledge of the <ulink type="http"
				url="http://www.genicam.org">GenICam</ulink> standard should
			help the user to understand how Aravis operates.
		</para>

		<para>
			Aravis currently provides an implementation of a gigabit ethernet UDP
			based protocol, found in a lot of ethernet industrial cameras.
		</para>

		<para>
			#ArvCamera is a simple API for easy access of standard camera features.
		</para>

		<para>
			#ArvDevice and #ArvGc are more low level APIs, which enable the full
			control of the cameras, allowing the use of the features specific to
			each model.
		</para>
	</chapter>

	<chapter id="thread-safety">
		<title>Thread Safety</title>

		<para>
			Aravis is not thread safe, which means one can not use the same object
			simultaneously from different threads, without using mutexes. But it is
		   	perfectly fine to use different aravis objects in different threads.
		</para>

		<para>
			A possible trap is that glib signal callbacks are called from the thread that
			emitted the corresponding signal. For example, the "new-buffer" callback is
			emitted from the stream packet receiving thread, which is an internal thread
			created by ArvGvStream. It is not safe to use ArvDevice and some ArvStream
			functions from this callback without using mutexes. The exceptions are
			#arv_stream_push_buffer, #arv_stream_pop_buffer, #arv_stream_try_pop_buffer and
			#arv_stream_timeout_pop_buffer.
		</para>
	</chapter>

	<chapter id="aravis-building">
		<title>Building and Debugging Aravis</title>

		<para>
			On UNIX, Aravis uses the standard GNU build system, using
			<application>autoconf</application> for package configuration
			and resolving portability issues,
			<application>automake</application> for building makefiles that
			comply with the GNU Coding Standards, and
			<application>libtool</application> for building shared
			libraries on multiple platforms.  The normal sequence for
			compiling and installing the Aravis library is thus:
			<literallayout>
				<userinput>./configure</userinput>
				<userinput>make</userinput>
				<userinput>make install</userinput>
			</literallayout>
		</para>

		<para>
			The standard options provided by <application>GNU
				autoconf</application> may be passed to the
			<command>configure</command> script.  Please see the
			<application>autoconf</application> documentation or run
			<command>./configure --help</command> for information about the
			standard options.
		</para>

		<para>
			In addition to the standard options, there is a number of options to activate or deactivate features.
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>--enable-gst-plugin enables the compilation of the aravissrc gstreamer element</listitem>
				<listitem>--enable-viewer makes the build system compile the viewer</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>

		<para>
			The ARV_DEBUG environment variable can be set to a comma
			separated list of debugging categories, which will make Aravis
			print out different types of debugging informations to the
			console. A debug level can also be specified, using a number from 0 (none) to
			3 (log) separated from the category name by a colon. For example, the
			following command before running an Aravis based application will make
			Aravis print out all stream and device related informations:
			<literallayout>
				<userinput>export ARV_DEBUG=stream:3,device:3</userinput>
			</literallayout>
			Available categories are:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>all</listitem>
				<listitem>interface</listitem>
				<listitem>device</listitem>
				<listitem>stream</listitem>
				<listitem>stream-thread</listitem>
				<listitem>gvcp</listitem>
				<listitem>gvsp</listitem>
				<listitem>genicam</listitem>
				<listitem>evaluator</listitem>
				<listitem>dom</listitem>
				<listitem>misc</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</chapter>
</part>
